http://stpancraschurch.org/about/privacy-policy/

HS2 / EAP
St Mark’s, Cuamba (Mozambique)
St Peter’s, Chelsea (New York)
The Portico Project 2014-2016
360° Tour (Google)
HS2 / EAP
St Mark’s, Cuamba (Mozambique)
St Peter’s, Chelsea (New York)
The Portico Project 2014-2016
360° Tour (Google)
The Parochial Church Council (PCC) of St Pancras Church
Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
Who are we?
The PCC of St Pancras Church is the data controller (contact details below).  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
How do we process your personal data?
The PCC of St Pancras Church complies with its obligations under the GDPR by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
to inform you of news, events, activities and services running at St Pancras Church;
to provide appropriate pastoral and spiritual care for those who seek it;
to seek your views and comments;
to administer our membership records;
to raise funds and promote the interests of the church;
to enable us to meet all legal and statutory obligations, including maintaining and publishing our electoral roll under the Church Representation Rules and publishing banns of marriage;
to enable the Diocese of London and the Church of England to keep accurate records and co-ordinate the church’s mission and ministry in this area;
to carry out comprehensive safeguarding procedures with the aim of ensuring that all children and adults-at-risk are provided with safe environments;
to manage our employees, post-holders and volunteers;
to arrange the hire of church facilities;
to maintain our own accounts and records, including the processing of payments and gift aid applications;
our processing also includes the use of CCTV systems for the prevention and prosecution of crime
We will also process data about role holders for legal, personnel, administrative and management purposes and to enable us to meet our legal obligations, for example to pay role-holders, monitor their performance and to confer benefits in connection with your engagement as a Role Holder. ‘Role Holders’ include volunteers, employees, contractors, agents, staff, retirees, temporary employees, beneficiaries, workers, treasurers and other role holders.
We may process sensitive personal data relating to Role Holders including, as appropriate:
What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Processing operates with the explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations.
Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –
the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church (or with agents acting on the church’s behalf) where it is necessary for the performance of our tasks or where you first give us your prior consent. We will only share your data with third parties outside of the parish with your consent.
How long do we keep your personal data?We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide ‘Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records’ which is available from the Church of England website: https://www.churchofengland.org/more/libraries-and-archives/records-management-guides
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) until such time as they are sent to the London Metropolitan Archive.
Your rights and your personal data
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you. Any such request must be submitted in writing. A small fee may be payable if an information request is particularly onerous.
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information, but this may inhibit or limit the way in which St Pancras Church is able to interact with you. You may, at any time, change your mind about what information we hold about you, or if we continue to hold it at all, subject to any legal obligation on St Pancras Church to retain data.
You are responsible for the accuracy of data you have provided to St Pancras Church. If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
We may use your personal information to send you information about St Pancras Church and matters relating to our activities which we think may be of interest to you. We will only share data with trusted third parties where necessary for us to communicate with you (such as mailing companies for postal communications or through email campaigns or newsletters) or as stated above, and only once we are satisfied that any such use of data will accord with our privacy policy. We will not sell or share your personal information with any other charities, businesses or marketing companies without your explicit consent. You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the data we process. Persons processing data on behalf of St Pancras Church do so in accordance with this policy and on the basis that St Pancras Church is satisfied that they can and will adhere to our high standards for data protection and security.
The transmission of information over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.
Web Browsing and Cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
We may also collect and store information about your browsing device, including, where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type. This is anonymous statistical data about your browsing activities and patterns, and does not contain any personal data.
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy policy.
Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints please in the first instance contact:
The Vicar, Parish Office, St Pancras Church, Euston Road, London NW1 2BA
020 7388 1416     vicar@stpancraschurch.org
You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF.
March 2019
For nearly 200 years St Pancras Church on the Euston Road has gathered people together to worship God, to learn more about the Christian faith, and to serve the local community. Come and be part of its continuing story.
Make a donationPlease consider making a donation towards the maintenance of the Church and the good work that we do in the community.
Weekly Services
Holy Communion:
Monday - Thursday:
Sunday:
11am - 2pm
11am - 1pm
Recent Tweets
A very warm welcome to Miriam Campbell who started work today as the new Parish Manager
@StPancrasChurch https://t.co/hcfdzzQmf8
October 5, 2020 via @
@StPancrasChurch &
@cryptgallery are open all weekend 10am-5pm as part of
@openhouselondon. Free guided tours depar… https://t.co/COH0pWr3JK
September 19, 2020 via @
RT
@RevFeital: Watch the space for our new Spiritual and arts programe
